So, so, so cute!
Where did it come from?
It sure is cute.
What are you all up to?
Anna, look at this thing.
So cute!
What is it?
Nice and smooth.
How long has it been here?
For about a week or so.
Huh, I had no idea.
Is it waiting here for someone?
Is this... Blade?
Episode 8
Less Than Human
I'm bored!
That's dangerous, Cu!
What was that anyway, Parent?
You remember how they said
I'll die if I use 15% of my strength?
So I figured I'd hone my fighting spirit
on a regular basis, and keep a stockpile.
Hey, Blade...
It looks like this thing's
been looking for you.
Instant Dragon Eater!
Oh, I did it!
Looks like I can fire off five more of these!
Blade!
Why'd you suddenly send that thing flying?!
My smooth friend...
Look, you have to destroy them!
Why would you do that?!
The poor thing!
It's been looking for you!
Don't you know what it is?
That thing's a Guardian!
A Guardian?
What's that?
Um, um...
Should I try and fix it up?
Just leave it.
That thing can handle being
wrecked over and over.
Ugh, this sucks, though.
Did it come up aboveground looking for me?
Is she an acquaintance of Blade's?
Will this body do?
Eh?
I have analyzed the human male psyche,
and designed an appearance to
arouse your protective instincts.
Hold on, who are you?
Hey, Blade...
Do you think she's the one from yesterday?
Dragon Eater!
Dragon Eater! Dragon Eater! Dragon Eater!
Blade?!
W-Wait!
That's too much!
You're going overboard!
Dragon Eater!
Phew, that was a close one!
You lousy superorganism!
What are you doing?!
You're up against a girl!
Don't you feel sorry for her?!
Why am I the bad guy here?
Besides, I'm sure that in no time...
See? She's back!
Yeah.
Okay, let's do this.
Hold on a second!
Besides, I don't think she's dangerous.
Are you sure she doesn't
just want to be friends?
There's no way!
Guardians are bad news!
If they go berserk, then even worse news!
I have received a command to eradicate you.
Currently, I am in
observation mode to gather data.
See, told you!
Hey, hey...
Want to take classes with us?
You are not an eradication target.
However, stand in my way,
and I will eliminate you.
Furthermore, I am not programmed
to perform collaborative tasks.
In that case, you can learn how
to do that with everyone here!
Well, Iona?
Iona?
That says Iona in ancient writing,
doesn't it?
This is not read as Iona, but 1-0-N-A.
It is my identification and model number,
and therefore, not my name.
I see!
But if you don't have a name,
I can call you Iona, right?
It's just like Claire to come on so strongly.
And if you really want to defeat Blade...
We can all come up with a plan together!
Wait, why?!
How does that sound?
Let us begin discussing
methods to eradicate Blade!
Hey, Iona...
Why Blade, anyway?
That is because...
he forcefully infiltrated my intimate zone,
desecrating my chassis repeatedly each time.
That's awful, Blade.
Hold it right there!
All I did was trespass on
the area she was guarding!
What's more, I had the master key, didn't I?
I borrowed it from the king.
That is insufficient.
I also require biometric authentication
and a master code genetic signature.
What's this about?
The Royal Library of Banned Books
is underground near here.
I had to drop in a bit to
look up things about Asmodeus.
What?!
So you mean it's because you were helping me?
There were 13 more instances
of trespassing prior to that.
It wasn't my fault at all.
I was destroyed 28 times in total...
Blade, that's way too many times!
With my body being divided
into 577,526 fragments...
Blade, that's way too many pieces!
And reprimanded by Mother, my supervisor,
for 500,037,000 milliseconds...
Your boss lectures you for way too long!
She attacked me first, so I had
no choice but to fight back.
Blade, you're so merciless!
Blade, that's way too mean!
Your heinous behavior sickens
even the Demon King.
I'm leaving!
We made him sulk.
Blade.
Everyone's so mean!
I only broke into the library because
of my duties as the Great Hero!
Yes. I know.
Besides, those things keep their
souls in a separate location,
so it's not like they die when
you destroy their bodies.
If they did die upon destruction,
what would you do?
Well, I mean... I'd have to think about it.
I'm not the Great Hero now, anyway.
Feast your eyes on this!
I believe this is the
reason why Iona can't win!
You mean Blade is relentless because
she doesn't die, even when destroyed?
Oh, totally.
I could see that.
Blade can be so weirdly cold,
and downright scary at times.
He even told me he'd cut me down!
Bragging, are we?
I've got my share of stories, too.
N-No, I'm not!
Never mind that.
Let's be a little more constructive.
Never mind that?!
I thin we should focus on ways
to prevent your defeat for now.
This is the result of my thought process.
Why did you decide to look like a girl?
Upon observation, I determined
that he treats women more gently.
So you figured he'd go easy on you this way?
That's adorable!
I want to adopt her!
So cute!
Iona.
I've come up with a strategy.
I call it...
the Stand Alone Complex!
Let me give a simple explanation.
We directly install Iona's soul
within the Core Unit in her heart,
placing it in a state
capable of being destroyed.
Huh? But if you do that...
Yes. Iona will cease to
become indestructible.
Would Blade take her down knowing that?
You can do it, Parent!
Get him! Beat him to a bloody pulp!
Iona! Good luck!
Go, go! Do your best!
Okay, let's get on with ti!
Blade.
Let me tell you this first.
Right now, I am in Stand Alone mode.
What? Stand Alone?
Presently, my connection to Mother
has been physically severed.
That is to say, I am operating
fully independently,
and cannot be repaired if I am destroyed.
Huh? Hold on...
Since your soul is in a different location...
My weak point is currently right here.
Hey, there's no reason
to make him cop a feel!
Ten centimeters deep inside
lies my heart and soul.
If it sustains severe damage,
I as an individual unit will
forever cease to exist.
Do you comprehend?
Now, then...
Hey!
Ow!
What is the matter?
Why, you!
Dragon...
Damn it!
Wind pressure alone isn't gonna cut it, huh?
If so...
The superorganism is grunting and groaning!
She's not half bad.
It really looks like Blade
can't lay a finger on her!
That smarts!
I'm gonna have a bump now!
Go a little easy, won't you?
Blade, you are the one who will go easy.
I already know it is not in your nature to
employ violence against an innocent girl.
You were defeated because your
attacks are too powerful.
That's not all.
You also didn't give me any chance
to use my less powerful moves.
Now then, please surrender.
Or would you like to grunt
and groan some more?
I give, I give!
I admit defeat.
She beat Blade!
How frustrating!
That's amazing, Iona!
Ow...
Iona.
V for victory.
You're not gonna eat it?!
Or wait, can you even eat?
I am equipped to break down and
absorb organic matter as energy.
However...
You're not feeling hungry?
I believe she's lost motivation
after defeating Blade, her target,
resulting in burnout syndrome.
But doesn't that only apply to humans?
If I am met with a matter that
I cannot resolve on my own,
would it be best to discuss it with others?
If you've got problems, tell us about them!
We're all your friends.
In times like these, I would always
turn to Mother for guidance.
Who is this Mother?
She means the Mother Computer.
The one who supervises Iona.
Whenever I complete a given command,
I report it to Mother and
am assigned my next mission.
However, even though I have
restored the connection,
Mother continues to refuse it.
For abandoning my duties, unilaterally
blocking the connection, and other reasons,
it seems that I have been declared a
defective unit and my terminal login expunged.
So you mean... you got fired?
What are these other reasons?
Transmitting around 15 terabytes' worth
of written abuse aimed at Mother.
There's your reason.
I am feeling terribly insecure,
now that I am without a supervisor.
Peek. Stare.
Blade.
Can I call you Master?
No way!
You're asking me to take the
place of your supervisor, right?
That is unfortunate.
If I do not have you become my master,
the counter will keep ticking.
Counter?
Yes.
To prevent them turning berserker
without a chain of command,
all Guardians have a
self-destruct program installed.
What?!
It looks like it decrements every second,
which means we have a
little over 84 hours left.
Do not fear.
My intent is to self-destruct in a
location with no one else around.
That's not the issue here!
Ah, I get it already.
That counter should stop if I become
your master or whatever, right?
Yes, most likely.
I'll do it then.
I'll be your master.
Thank you very much, Master.
Here you go, Master.
Tonkatsu curry!
By the way, what's with the getup?
It's so spicy!
It is an ancient attire for servants.
If you command me to stop wearing it, I will.
No, you don't have to stop.
I have received your command.
I will cease to stop wearing it.
What is your next command?
It's nice having you take care of me,
but it feels like I've lost my freedom.
She provides us with food and snacks!
That's a good thing!
No, it's not.
Sophie?
What's wrong?
If you've got something to say,
then you should say it.
Is that a command?
Huh? Yeah, sure.
That is not fair, Master.
You will not command me,
yet you do so for Miss Sophie.
You be quiet.
Oh, is that a command?
I don't like this.
Get off him!
What don't you like?
She's stealing my character traits!
Huh?
She's stealing my character traits.
For one, my expressionless face.
I am not expressionless.
I have 800 different facial
expressions installed.
Also, how I wait for commands.
That is inevitable.
I am simply following my
instincts as an android.
Stare...
You don't ever give me commands.
Yet here you are, ordering Iona around.
This isn't fair.
In that case, let us see which of
us is more deserving of Master.
Eh? Eh?!
I've heard of this!
This is what they call a scene of carnage!
Let there be blood!
I'm begging you,
please don't cause any trouble.
Is that a command?
Y-Yeah.
Meow.
No, don't give me that.
What are you doing?
Establishing my character.
Do you think I can beat Iona now?
I see.
It seems we both had the same idea.
Let us have a staring contest instead.
Just what I wanted.
I don't care anymore.
An unarmed showdown?
They couldn't settle the staring contest
even after a whole day had passed.
It seems I will have to resort to this.
Artificial Great Hero Power.
This is supposed to be unarmed combat!
Both of you are disqualified.
Master. Which of us is more skilled?
Pick the one that feels nicer.
I can't tell the difference.
Huh?
You're going to watch me as I'm fast asleep?
What kind of showdown is this, even?
The one to serve Master must be
someone who always puts you at ease.
Go on, Blade.
Sleep like a baby.
Okay, I'm turning the lights off.
Feel free to go to sleep if
you are tired, Miss Sophie.
I've undergone sleep training.
I can keep going for up to seven days.
I do not require sleep in the first place.
It seems we will not decide
a victor today, either.
Agreed.
Lately, I feel as though I would be
okay if we never settled this matter.
I have always been alone.
Always alone, for such a long time.
He was the only one who would come visit me.
I was all alone as well.
All alone in my cage in that dark lab.
I was nobody.
The single link I had was
my worth as his replica.
I was able to stay linked with the
world because he was there for me.
That's how I felt.
I also felt the same way.
It seems that you have become
someone special to me as well.
What should I do about this?
I'm not sure.
But this feeling when I compete against you...
Am I having fun?
I do not know the answer to that question.
Miss Sophie.
As a human, you are better equipped to...
Sophie.
Pardon?
Just call me Sophie.
No title needed.
Understood, Sophie.
Good morning, Sophie.
Good morning, Iona.
Looks like you two are good friends now.
Well? Are you having fun at school?
Yes. Very much so.
Iona. Show me the counter.
Is that a command?
That's right. Show me.
It's gone down!
But why?
So it didn't work...
I would not say that
there has been no effect.
The progression of the counter has
slowed down to one-tenth the speed.
Let me take a look.
I was afraid that a human as your master
wouldn't work, not even when it's a superorganism.
Looks like there's about 20 hours left.
What do you want to do?
I would...
If possible, until the last moment,
I would like to be with you
all for as long as possible.
Iona...
After that, I will go by myself.
I do not wish to cause
injury to anyone around me.
Let's get the "Send Iona Off
with a Smile" party underway!
Is it all right for me to remain here?
Yeah.
Everyone is trying to
make your wish come true.
So, Iona...
You should also enjoy this
time as much as you can.
I don't mean that as a command,
but as your friend.
Yes.
Anna.
Did you find that idiot?
We've looked all over the campus,
but he's nowhere to be found.
Where has that Blade gone
off to at a time like this?
Iona!
Thank you very much for today.
I am destined to expire soon.
What meaning is there in appending a
meager amount of data to my memory?
At first, I could not understand it.
However, after spending time with you all,
in the moment before destruction,
I see myself for the first time
and feel as though I understand you humans.
Sophie.
I was less than human, but thanks to you,
I was able to become human.
Please give Master my regards.
Claire.
I still remember the warmth of your hands.
Yessica.
I would have liked to have
more girl talk with you.
Mao.
I leave it to you to eradicate Master.
Cu.
It is fine to be mischievous,
so please grow to be fine and mighty.
Finally, Earnest...
The truth is that I am scared.
I do not want to go away.
Help me.
I'm sorry, Iona!
I'm so sorry.
Do not forget me!
Please, do not forget me!
I won't forget you!
I won't, either!
I won't forget!
I won't forget you. I swear.
Thank you.
Farewell.
Huh?
She's not detonating.
What's going on here?
It should already be time.
Oh, this is where it leads?
Huh? Where's the party?
Wait, is there no food left for me?
Blade!
Where have you been this whole time,
skipping the party like that?!
Ah, I went to go see Mother.
What?
Why?
Well, you were gonna explode
because Mother fired you, right?
That's why...
I went to go persuade her.
With a bit of brute force, as well.
The connection with Mother has been restored.
Does that mean...
Currently, the self-destruct program...
has met none of its parameters to activate.
Sophie, I...
Yes.
What you want most right now.
You should go and do it.
If that was the case—
Master!
Master! Master!
Well? Not going to stop her?
Just for today...
Master!
Can't breathe...
I changed my mind after all!
Get off!
Get off him!
Next Time
The Superorganism Suppression Committee